Isaac Anane Amankwaah

Software Developer

Accra, Ghana

LINKEDIN PROFILE - https://bit.ly/3wwCQGg GITHUB PROFILE - https://github.com/brasmith9

+233 54 131 2238 | +233 50 023 2643 developer.anane@gmail.com

About

Fullstack Developer and an inspirational mentor with over 4 years of experience in software development. Recognized for demonstrating strong analytical skills and proven software development skills. Expert in JavaScript, PHP and Python. Resourceful and well-organized with excellent leadership and team-building record. Creative in solving problems and always coming up with innovative ideas. Excellent in working as part of a team or individually. Effective and articulate communicator with all levels of employees and perfect with googling.

Experience

Christ Goodness Educational Center / Bursar

JUNE 2015 - AUGUST 2016, KUMASI, GHANA

- Used spreadsheets and databases to maintain financial records.
- Supplemented office staff by assisting with scanning, photocopying, faxing, and report data input.
- Kept office supplies well organized and sufficiently stocked, placing orders promptly to replenish materials before depleted.

Perigee Insights (Pi) Limited / Software Developer (NATIONAL SERVICE) AUGUST 2020 - AUGUST 2021, ACCRA, GHANA

- Used Javascript, SQL, and PHP to develop app solutions.
- Discussed project progress with clients, collected feedback on different stages, and directly addressed concerns.
- Reviewed code, debugged problems, and corrected issues.
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs, and enhancements.
- Collaborated with in-house web designers to create sleek and innovative User Interfaces.

Perigee Insights (Pi) Limited / Senior Software Developer AUGUST 2021 - FEBRUARY 2022, ACCRA, GHANA

- Created visual concepts of clients' ideas with various design tools.
- Collaborated with other developers to build stable APIs.
- Performed frontend coding during development sprint to produce excellent and scalable UI.
- Implemented unit and integrated testing for all the systems developed.

- Liaised with the Product Development team to plan new features
- Mentored and helped Junior Developers and Interns

Enyata Software Engineering Limited - Ghana / Senior Backend Engineer

FEBRUARY 2022 - PRESENT, ACCRA, GHANA

- Engaged in code reviews and debugging to ensure quality product delivery.
- Collaborated with other developers to build stable APIs.
- Implemented unit and integrated testing for all the systems developed.
- Liaised with the Product Development team to plan new features
- Mentored and helped Junior Developers and Interns.

Education

University of Cape Coast / BSc. Actuarial Science

AUGUST 2016 - JULY 2020, CAPE COAST, GHANA

Completed with a second-class lower division in Actuarial Science. Major courses include mathematics, Statics, Economics, and business management.

St. Hubert Seminary SHS / Business (WASSCE)

SEPTEMBER 2012 - MAY 2015, KUMASI, GHANA

Completed with excellent marks in business studies. Major subjects include Elective Mathematics, Economics, Accounting, and Business Management.

Software Skills

JavaScript / Node.JS

EXPERT, 3 YEARS EXPERIENCE

Demonstrated excellent skills in Javascript Language in both front-end and backend. I have worked with Vue.JS and React.JS for frontend development and Express.JS for backend development.

PHP

EXPERT, 3 YEARS EXPERIENCE

Expert in PHP using its popular framework, Laravel for API development.

Python

EXPERT, 4 YEARS EXPERIENCE

I use Python language for web development (Django Framework), Data Analysis, Web scrapping, and Machine Learning.

Database Management

EXPERT

- MYSQL
- POSTGRES SQL
- MongoDB

OTHER TOOLS

EXPERT

- GIT
- GRAPHQL
- POSTMAN

Projects / Achievements

ACTUARIAL SOCIETY OF GHANA WEBSITE

https://www.asg.org.gh/

Single-handedly redesigned the website for the Actuarial Society of Ghana.

Major modules include Online Member Registration/ Verification, Dues Payment Module, News Module, and Articles/ Publications Module. Etc.

VANGUARD LIFE ASSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED

https://osa.vanguardlife.com/

Participated as the team lead - A web app for life policy administration. Major modules include Claims Management Module, Online Premium / Claims Payment Module, Bulk SMS / Email Module, and Messaging Module.

PERIGEE (PI) INSIGHTS LIMITED

PiClaim Project

Participated as the team lead - An Insurance-Pensions aggregator system built with Python's Django Framework. Major Modules include Claim Management System, Real-time Chat System, Fraud Detection module, Rating Bureau, etc.

RUK FINANCE LIMITED

http://rukfinance.io/

Web App which enables clients to subscribe to the company's digital products. Major modules include, Online Payment module, Client Subscription Module, etc.

ENYATA SOFTWARE ENGINEERING LIMITED

HRMS Project

Web app developed purposely for Human Resource management. Major modules are, Job creation and hiring modules, live messaging modules, etc.

Activities

Actuarial Science Students' Association of Ghana / Treasurer

MAY 2018 - APRIL 2019

Working directly with the Finance committee of the association to oversee the finances, funding, fundraising, sales, financial planning and budgeting, financial reporting, banking, and bookkeeping through the use of Microsoft Excel and Word.

Actuarial Science Students' Association of Ghana / President

MAY 2019 - APRIL 2020

I was responsible for the overall well-being of the members of the association and also ensuring that the various committees and designations perform up to the expectation.

Mentorship / Course Instructor

1. Actuarial Society of Ghana MAY 2020 AND MAY 2021

Graduate Assistance Training - I handled the Microsoft Excel VBA class. I introduced them to the language and we developed two real-world programs applicable in the Insurance industry.

2. Enyata Academy

MAY 2022 - AUGUST 2022

I took the academy students from absolute beginner level in Javascript through to a complete Nodejs mastery course specializing in Backend Development.

Reference

Makafui Aheto / Managing Partner

PERIGEE INSIGHTS LIMITED

ma.aheto@perigeeinsights.io/maheto001@st.uq.edu.qh

Ammiel Yawson / Senior Frontend Engineer

ENYATA SOFTWARE ENGINEERING LIMITED

<u>ammiel@enyata.com</u> / ammielgyanyawson@gmaill.com